Crime, passion and lust for power.
Once Upon a Time in America is a drama, crime film directed by Sergio Leone.
A former Prohibition-era Jewish gangster returns to the Lower East Side of Manhattan over thirty
years later, where he once again must confront the ghosts and regrets of his old life.
David 'Noodles' Aaronson, played by Robert De Niro.
Maximilian 'Max' Bercovicz, played by James Woods.
Deborah Gelly, played by Elizabeth McGovern.
James Conway O'Donnell, played by Treat Williams.
Carol, played by Tuesday Weld.
Frankie Monaldi, played by Joe Pesci.
Once Upon a Time in America (Italian: C'era una volta in America) is a 1984 epic crime
film based on Harry Grey's semi-autobiographical 1952 novel The Hoods.
Directed by Sergio Leone from a screenplay he co-wrote with Leonardo Benvenuti, Piero De Bernardi, Enrico Medioli, Franco Arcalli and Franco
Ferrini, the film stars Robert De Niro, James Woods, Elizabeth McGovern, Joe Pesci, Burt Young, Tuesday Weld and Treat Williams.
The film is an Italian–American venture produced by The Ladd Company, Embassy International
Pictures, PSO Enterprises and Rafran Cinematografica, and distributed by Warner Bros.
It chronicles the lives of best friends David "Noodles" Aaronson and Maximilian "Max" Bercovicz as they lead a group of
Jewish ghetto youths who rise to prominence as Jewish gangsters in New York City's world of organized crime.
The film explores themes of childhood friendships, love, lust, greed, betrayal, loss and
broken relationships, together with the rise of mobsters in American society.
It is the final film directed by Leone before his death five years later,
and the first feature film that he had directed in 13 years.
It is also the third installment of Leone's Once Upon a Time Trilogy, which
includes Once Upon a Time in the West (1968) and Duck, You Sucker!
The cinematography is by Tonino Delli Colli, and
the film score by Ennio Morricone.
Leone originally envisaged two three-hour films, then a single 269-minute (4 hours and 29 minutes) version,
but was convinced by distributors to shorten it to 229 minutes (3 hours and 49 minutes).
The American distributors, The Ladd Company, further shortened it to 139 minutes (2 hours and 19
minutes), and rearranged the scenes into chronological order, without Leone's involvement.
The US edit was a critical and commercial flop in the United States, and critics
who had seen both versions harshly condemned the changes made.
The original "European cut" has remained a critical favorite and frequently appears in
lists of the greatest films of all time, especially in the gangster genre.
The film explores themes of new york city, regret,
lovesickness, rape, life and death.
The tone is emotional.